Hung Nguyen

Software Engineer | London, UK (Flexible Relocation)

hnguyen@cs.stanford.edu | UK: +44 07919 507177 US: +1 (832) 361-0190 | cs.stanford.edu/~hnguyen

Summary

Software engineer with expertise in using Swift and Unity C# to build well-designed, human-centered experiences. Developed core UX libraries and backend integrations at an MIT Media Lab startup, worked with new immersive technologies at Apple, and improved documentation and processes across all roles. Committed to delivering intuitive products to solve problems and enhance lives.

Work Experience

iOS Software Engineer, Self-Employed

Remote | 06.2023 - Present

- Integrated machine learning algorithms using Vision and Sound Analysis with immersive (AR/VR) content
- · Built codebases with world understanding and hand tracking with TCA library
- Utilized SwiftData and CloudKit infrastructure for automatic data storage/saves management
- · Optimized custom-built shaders for Reality Composer environments
- Released multiple immersive utility visionOS apps on App Store

VR/AR Software Engineer, Three Space Lab

Remote | 08.2020 - 06.2023

- Integrated services into PC/standalone VR Unity projects (e.g. Google Analytics, Zoom, Discord GameSDK)
- Developed networked (remote multi-user) 2D and 3D interaction systems & interaction features
- Built Swagger wrapper client to manage cloud file sync with integration tests
- · Trained new employees with development tooling and procedures; facilitated user tests

Mobile Software Research Assistant, The Wall Lab

Stanford, CA | 01.2020 - 08.2020

- Offloaded gameplay images to S3, and allow for dynamic loading as needed
- Incorporated fun into prototype experiences using ARKit and competitive game modes

Software Engineering Intern, Apple Inc.

Sunnyvale, CA | 06.2019 - 09.2019

- Designed and developed an internal SceneKit-ARKit visualization framework
- Integrated and optimized new CV algorithms across devices while visualizing the related telemetry

Software Engineering Intern, *OneWeb*

Hybrid - Los Altos, CA | 06.2017 - 09.2017

- Created and deployed a cross-platform AR attitude application for offline, low-power satellite antenna alignment
- · Led weekly meetings and presentations; collaborated with other teams to deliver metrics

Other Experiences

Unity Developer, Inclusive User Testing in VR

Boston, MA | 03.2022

- Integrated Google STT, Azure TTS, and screenshot sharing to server for accessible user reporting
- Won XR Reality Hack's XR for Inclusion award

Electronics Workshop Instructor, Stage One Education

Boston, MA | 03.2022 - 03.2023

· Mentored secondary school students in Arduino/CAD workshops

Cryptography Researcher, Fidelius

Stanford, CA | 03.2018 - 07.2018

• Implemented API to help transfer I/O data between origin server and an Intel SGX enclave

Education

Stanford University | Computer Science

Palo Alto, CA | 09.2016 - 06.2020

- System Courses: Operating Systems, Compilers, Intro to Cryptography, Computer & Network Security, Web Programming Fundamentals, Programming Languages
- Design Courses: VR: The Possibility and Peril of Immersive Art, Designing Serious Games, Intro to Mechatronics, Design for Accessibility